KEESHA HARGROVE

FULL-STACK ENGINEER

Experienced web developer who understands web applications, relational databases, as well as software engineering, coding, and programming. Having the skill to work cooperatively and solve problems effectively is vital in a fast-paced environment. Full-Stack engineer who is passionate about developing and polishing existing features, and understands the impact of the interface on user experience.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Coding: Front-End Development • Software & React Development • Programming • APIs • HTML/CSS Best Practices • Systems Engineering • User Experience (UX) • User Interface (UI) • Object-Oriented Programming

Data Management: Business Intelligence Analysis • Relational Database (Postgres) • Web Technologies Management

Testing: UI/UX Design • UI/UX Design Principles • Application Debugging • API Testing • Test-Driven Development

Leadership: People Management • Empathetic Attitude • Problem-Solving • Reliability • ADA Compliance • Communication Skills

Writing: Software Documentation Maintenance • Instructional Sets • Research & Technical Documentation

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

PROGRAMMING: HTML ➤ CSS ➤ EXPRESS ➤ JAVASCRIPT ➤ NODE.JS ➤ NODE.JS

FRAMEWORKS & SOFTWARE: MySQL ➤ POSTGRES ➤ REACT ➤ MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE (WORD, EXCEL, POWERPOINT)

OS: WINDOWS, LINUX

CERTIFICATES & TRAINING

FULL-STACK ONLINE WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATION

▼ Flatiron School, August 2021

Key Modules: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, React.js, Git, UX basics, "How to build fast, modern, dynamic and responsive web apps," "Programming with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript for front-end, and back-end," Using external APIs, Version control with Git & GitHub, Team & Pair Programming, Programming Logic

PROJECTS

- Capstone movie review app using HTML/CSS/JS/RAILS -- Models (ActiveRecords) handle relationships, validations, and logic using CRUD. Determines the view to use and makes the data available as instance variables
- ✓ Capstone project on business contact index React, Redux, HTML/CSS/JS Implemented reusable components in React for a simple website

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

- Performed assigned duties consistently in order to contribute to a positive, empowering work environment.
- Completed inspection reports, summarized rework and data, and entered inspection data into a quality database.
- Engaging in regular training and education to keep job knowledge current.

LEADERSHIP & COLLABORATION

- ✓ Coordinated and communicated with other shifts and departmental management on a daily basis to improve service and teamwork.
- ✓ Engaging in regular training and education to keep job knowledge current.
- Contacted and responded to customers and customer complaints in a timely manner.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

CUSTOMER SERVICE REP X FRUIT INC X Durham, NC12/2017 − PRESENTQUALITY CONTROL X MGS X REMOTE02/2012 − 02/2021FRONT DESK REP X BEST WESTERN X OXFORD, NC02/2007 − 03/2012

EDUCATION

MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, Ashford University B.A. EARLY CHILDHOOD ADMINISTRATION, Ashford University